（王騎(おうき)）ンンッ！
（龐煖(ほうけん)）バカな… 何なのだ？ 貴様
Madness...
What are you...?
（龐煖）き… 貴様は一体 何者だ！
Wh-What in the world are you?!
（王騎）
ンフフフッ… 決まってるでしょう
Isn't it obvious?
The greatest general under the heavens!
天下の大将軍ですよ！
Wang Qi!
王騎！
（兵士）将軍！
General!
（信(しん)）ンッ！
Xin!
（尾平(びへい)）信！
（信）ヤッ！
Like hell I'm gonna let you die!
（信）死なせてたまるかよ！
絶対 連れて帰るからな！
I'm gonna make sure I get you home!
The setting is before the common era, in the Spring and Autumn Warring States Period.
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）時は紀元前 春秋戦国時代
Xin, the boy that came from obscurity to become the general of a Hundred-Man Unit
名もなき存在から
百人隊の将にまでなった少年 信は
is now at the center of a historic battle.
今 歴史的な戦いの中心にいた
秦国(しんこく)総大将 王騎と
趙国(ちょうこく)総大将 龐煖の一騎打ち
A one-on-one battle between the State of Qin Supreme Commander, Wang Qi,
and the State of Zhao Supreme Commander, Pang Nuan.
因縁深き その戦いに
国家の命運が握られていた
Gripped in that deeply personal battle
is the fate of a kingdom.
Presented by Anime-Destiny
itsumo yori hayaku kietetta hoshi zora ni
いつもより早く消えてった星空に
In a starry sky that disappeared faster than it ever has
Translation
kewl0210
kusanariatta deai wa
重なり合った出会いは
the many piled up meetings we've had
Editing
jagman1x3
ore wo nomikonde iku
俺を呑み込んでいく
swallow me.
kono yume wa kudakenai
この夢は砕けない
This dream cannot be broken.
Timing
rtrs
sabitsukaseta kyoufushin
錆びつかせた恐怖心
Among this rusted fear in my heart
yuragu fuan no naka de
揺らぐ不安の中で
and the anxiety that makes me waver
Typesetting
kewl0210
ame wo saegiru shinjitsu
雨を遮る信実
is a truth that interrupts the rain.
dare ni mo ubaeyashinai
誰にも奪えやしない
No one can take it away,
Karaoke
kewl0210
FZeroWing
onaji keshiki ni hisonda puraido
同じ景色にひそんだプライド
our pride that lurks in the same landscape.
Encode
max80
itsuka kitto kanau ima mo mieru kibou fortitude
いつかきっと叶う 今も見える希望 fortitude
The fortuitous desire I have will definitely come true one day.
yowasa wo sute wa shinai
弱さを捨てはしない
We won't throw away our weaknesses,
oretachi no kienai shiin
俺達の消えないシーン
those are scenes that won't disappear.
furenzokusen no youni hashiru kibou unbreakable heart
不連続線の様に走る希望 unbreakable heart
My desire in my unbreakable heart runs like a discontinuous line.
I knew at the start that there's no end.
QC
prefix-
I've made up my mind, right now it's the time to take the first step.
Distro
kokus
Kittie
prefix-
Now's the only time.
～♪
Succession
（伝令Ａ）報告！ 報告！
Report! Report!
龐煖さまが
見事 王騎を討ち取られました！
Lord Pang Nuan has killed Wang Qi!
（李牧(りぼく)）間違いありませんか？
（伝令Ａ）いや…
Are you certain of that?
（李牧）
間違いなく王騎は死んだのですね？
Are you absolutely certain that Wang Qi is dead?
あっ いえ… 私が見たときは
まだ息がありましたが
Ah, no... When I saw him he was still breathing, but...
Lord Pang Nuan's lance pierced Wang Qi's chest.
龐煖さまの矛は 王騎の胸を貫き
もはや時間の問題かと…
It's a matter of time at this point...
（伝令Ｂ）
報告！ 右方の端で異変が！
Report!
An abnormal event on the right edge!
一部の秦兵が暴れ回り
右軍に被害が出ています！
A group of Qin soldiers are on a rampage and there's been damage to the right army!
Urgent report!
（伝令Ｃ）急報！
（趙兵）こ… 今度は何だ？
Wh-What is it this time?!
（伝令Ｃ）正面より 敵が
この本陣 目がけて突進してきます
From the front, the enemy is charging forward, targeting these headquarters!
Lord Pang Nuan!
（趙兵）
龐煖さま 追われぬのですか？
Are you not going to follow him?!
（趙兵）このままではヤツらが…
At this rate, they will...!
（隊長）追撃だ！ 隊列を組め！
Pursue them!
Get in formation!
つまらぬ
Worthless...
（趙兵）秦兵が来るぞ！
Qin soldiers are coming!
Kill them!
（趙兵）殺せ！ 殺せ！
（昂(こう)）ム… ムリだ
敵だらけで 助かりっこない！
Th... This is impossible!
There are enemies everywhere!
We've got no chance of saving him!
（趙兵）あれが王騎だ！
That's Wang Qi!
（趙兵）首を取れ！
（信）なっ…
Take his head!
（親衛隊員Ａ）
行け 小僧！ 殿を… 殿を！
Go, kid!
Lord... Bring Lord...
Bastard!
（趙兵）おのれ！
（親衛隊員Ａ）
たとえ どんな姿になろうと
殿を城へ お帰しするのだ！
No matter what shape he's in,
bring Lord back to the castle!
I feel a pain deep inside my chest, don't you...?
（李牧）胸の奥が痛いですね
That is why I hate war.
（李牧）だから 戦は嫌いです
（カイネ）
王騎の死は もはや明白なのに
Wang Qi's death is already evident, and yet...
全員が あんなに必死で…
they're still moving so desperately...
They know full well that if the corpse goes into possession of us, the State of Zhao,
（李牧）
亡骸(なきがら)を我が趙国が手にすれば―
辱めの限りを尽くすことは
分かりきっていますからね
it would be the height of disgrace.
逆の立場なら―
If the positions were reversed...
私たちも 死など惜しまず
鬼となって戦います
we would fight like demons, undaunted by a thing like death.
いちばん怖いかもしれない
今の秦国軍が
They might be most fearsome right now...
the State of Qin Army.
ヤバイ！
Oh no!
（信）王騎将軍！
General Wang Qi!
（親衛隊員たち）殿！
Lord!
Lord! We will protect you!
（親衛隊員Ｂ）
殿！ 我らがお守りします！
This is quite good for someone of your standing, Youngster Qin.
（王騎）童 信のぶんざいで
やるじゃありませんか
私以外で 我が愛馬 凰(おう)を御す者を
初めて見ましたよ
You're the first person I've seen manage my beloved horse, Huang, besides me.
（信）馬が勝手に走ってんだよ
俺は何もしてない
The horse is riding on its own. I didn't do anything.
ンフッ…
（王騎）童 信… 背筋を伸ばし
目を閉じて 深呼吸なさい
Youngster Xin,
please straighten your back, close your eyes, and breathe deeply.
えっ？ いや だけど 今は…
Huh? But right now, we're...
（握り締める音）
いてっ！
Ow!
（王騎）目を閉じて 深呼吸です
（信）痛(いて)え… 分かったよ！
Close your eyes and breathe deeply.
That hurts! Okay, I get it!
（信）ハァ…
（王騎）凰は 正に将軍の馬です
Huang is truly a general's horse.
Right now, you are riding a full general's horse on a battlefield.
あなたは今 この戦場の中で
将軍の馬に乗って走っているのです
理解したら ゆっくり目を開き
目にするものをよ～く見てみなさい
If you understand, slowly open your eyes.
And take a good look at what you see.
敵の軍を
The enemy army,
the enemy's faces,
敵の顔を
そして…
and...
味方の顔を
the faces of allies.
天と地を
The heavens and the earth.
これが将軍の見る景色です
This is the scenery a general sees.
ハァ…
（王騎）
ンフフフッ… どうですか？
How is it?
（信）“どう”って言われても…
（王騎）よく分かりませんか？
How?
Do you not fully understand?
（信）いや…
No...
少しは何か分かった気がする
I think I...
understood something...
In that moment, my whole body felt full to the brim with strength...
今の一瞬で 全身に力がみなぎった
（王騎）将軍の目には
さまざまなものが見えます
The eyes of a general can see many different things.
例えば ほら…
（信）ハッ…
For example, look.
The path of escape that should not have existed
（王騎）
なかったはずの活路が すぐそこに
will soon be there.
（壁(へき)）王騎将軍！
General Wang Qi!
壁のあんちゃん！
（壁）将軍！
Brother Bi!
General!
Well done, Bi.
（王騎）あっぱれです 壁
（壁）お迎えに上がりました！
私についてきてください！
I came to get you!
Please, come with me!
（蒙武(もうぶ)）ンンッ！
（壁）蒙武将軍が
必ずや道を開かれます！
General Meng Wu will be sure to open a path!
（趙兵たち）ウワッ！
ハアーッ！
オリャー！
General Meng Wu!
蒙武将軍！
ンフッ…
（壁）抜けたぞ！
（歓声）
We made it out!
（騰(とう)隊隊員）あとは我らに！
騰さまは 殿のおそばへ！
Leave the rest to us!
Lord Teng, go to Lord's side!
再び
乱世の全盛期が到来しそうですね
It seems another golden age of turbulent times has arrived...
王騎を追わなくてもよいのですか？
Are you sure you're not going to follow Wang Qi?
目的は 王騎の死
それが達せられた今―
My goal is the death of Wang Qi.
Now that that has been accomplished, there is no point in causing any more blood to be spilled.
これ以上 血を流すことに
全く意味はない
無意味な死だけは
絶対に許しません
I will not allow meaningless deaths!
今回の戦は ここまでです！
This war ends here!
誰ひとりとして
私のあとを追うことを禁じます
I forbid anyone from attempting to follow me.
軍長をはじめ １人もです
No combat commanders, not anyone.
騰…
Teng.
Yes, sir!
長く私を後ろで支えてくれましたが
You've long supported me at my back,
本来 あなたの実力は
私に見劣りしません
but your ability is honestly no less than mine.
この軍の先のこと一切を
あなたに委ねます
I entrust the future of this army completely to you.
Yes, sir.
Wang Qi!
（蒙武）王騎
（蒙武）許せ… 全て俺の責任だ
Forgive me. I bear full responsibility.
最後に何か言うことはあるか？
Are there any last words you would like to say to me?
蒙武… あなたの課題は明白です
Meng Wu,
your task is clear.
細かく言う必要もないでしょう
There is no need for detailed words.
（王騎）あなたは 間違いなく
秦国軍の顔になるべきひとり
You are without a doubt one who should become the face of the State of Qin Army.
そのことを自覚して
更なる成長を期待します
If you realize that yourself, I'd expect even more growth from you.
何しろ 今回 現れた趙の将軍は
いまだかつてない強敵です
In any case, the Zhao general that appeared today was an enemy stronger than any I've seen before.
He defeated me brilliantly in this battle.
今回は 見事に してやられました
ンフフフッ…
まったく 困ったものですねえ
Honestly, how troubling...
In any age, the military commanders that are called the strongest
いつの時代も
最強と称された武将たちは―
更なる つわものの出現で敗れます
are always defeated with the appearance of one even stronger.
中華の戦いは しばらく
その男を中心に回るでしょう
The battles in China will revolve around that man for a while, I expect...
しかし それもまた…
But he, as well,
次に台頭してくる武将に
討ち取られて 時代の舵(かじ)を渡す
will be beaten by the next military commander that emerges,
and hand over the helm of the era.
果てなき 男どもの命懸けの戦い
It is an endless battle of honorable men risking their lives.
Honestly,
まったく…
これだから 乱世は面白い
this is why tumultuous ages are interesting.
（王騎）童 信
Youngster Xin,
I promised to train you, didn't I?
修行をつけてやる約束でしたね
見てのとおり
もはやムリになってしまいました
As you can see, that is no longer possible.
しかし… そもそも 大将軍の私に
じかに教わろうなんて
But really, it was asking too much to be taught by a Great General like me in the first place.
虫がよすぎますよ ココココッ…
そういうことは 自分で戦場を
駆け回って学びなさい バカ者
So please, run about on battlefields and learn on your own, you idiot.
（王騎）
皆と共に修羅場をくぐりなさい
Survive scenes of carnage together with everyone.
You have potential, Xin.
素質はありますよ 信
Um...
あの…
（王騎）武に生き 一時代を築き…
To live for war,
create an era,
and finally die in battle was my true ambition...
更に 武に死ねることは本望
頼もしき次の時代の芽にも出会い
思い残すことはなく
I have even met with promising sprouts of the next age, and now without any regrets...
ようやく先に逝(い)った友たちのもとへ
I finally go to reach my comrades-in-arms that left before me...
摎(きょう)も笑っています
Liao is smiling as well.
Shi
Huang
Year
Wang
Qi
dies.
（兵士）趙軍が ひいていくぞ！
The Zhao Army is retreating!
（兵士たち）やったー！
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）
侵攻してきた趙国軍が撤退したため
一見 秦国軍の勝利にも見えた
Because the invading State of Zhao Army withdrew,
at a glance, it looked like the State of Qin's victory.
秦国にすれば―
Because for the State of Qin, preventing invasion meant their goal had been accomplished.
“侵攻を防ぐ”という目的を
達したからだ
But the group that witnessed the death of Wang Qi
しかし 王騎の死を
目の当たりにした一団は―
悲しみと悔しさのあまり
嗚咽(おえつ)が止まらなかった
could not stop weeping out of sadness and frustration.
All except for Teng, Meng Wu,
騰と蒙武
そして もう１人を除いては…
and one other.
王騎死亡の一報は
王宮にも届いていた
The death of Wang Qi also reached the royal palace.
（政(せい)）王騎は 出陣する前
俺に昭王(しょうおう)の遺言を伝えた
Wang Qi... before he departed for battle, he told me King Zhao's last will.
（昌文君(しょうぶんくん)）ハッ…
It was about the form of a king...
（政）それは 王たる姿…
全中華の王たる姿を
教えるものだった
The form of a king of all of China.
（王騎）最後に…
Finally...
“戦に慈悲は無用なれど―”
Although mercy in war is needless,
“奪い取った地にある民は
奴隷にあらず”
he does not make slaves out of the people of conquered lands.
“虐げることなく―”
He does not oppress them, but shows them the same love as he would the people of his kingdom.
“自国の民として
同様に愛を注ぐこと”
以上が
昭王より承っていた遺言です
That is all. It is the last will I was told by King Zhao.
（政）感謝する 王騎　今の話は
父からも教わっていなかった
You have my thanks, Wang Qi.
I did not even hear that from my father.
当然です　伝えておりませんので
（政）なに？
Of course. Because I did not tell it to him.
What?
（王騎）遺言は それを継ぐ資質の
ある王にのみ残されたものです
A last will only left to a king with the potential to succeed it.
昭王は
その判断を私に一任されました
King Zhao entrusted me to make that decision.
“私が仕えるに値すると
思う王にのみ伝えよ”と
To only tell it to a a king that I felt was deserved to have me serve them.
共に中華を目指しましょう 大王
Let us seek all of China together, your highness.
（泣き声）
あのバカは！
That idiot!
（政）王騎…
Wang Qi...
Half a Month Later
フゥ…
Hey! I'm back, Diao!
ただいま！ 帰ったぞ 貂(てん)！
あれ？
（貂）信！
（信）えっ？
Xin!
（貂）信… 良かった
Xin... I'm so glad...
無事だったか！
（信）ウワッ！
You're okay!
Ow!
いてっ！
That hurt, you idiot!
バカ！ 痛えよ お前
（貂）あっ ごめん つい…
Ah, sorry, I just...
でも 無事で ホント良かった
But... I'm really glad you're okay.
待たせたな　ひとりで暇だったろう
I guess I kept you waiting a while.
You must have had nothing to do on your own.
（貂）
はぁ？ 何言ってんだよ？ お前
Huh? What're you talking about?
俺は戦に出てたんだぞ
（信）はぁ？
I went out to the war!
忘れたのか？
Did you forget?!
自分の場所を見つけるために
俺も戦に出るっつっただろう！
I told you I was going to the war to find my place!
ああ～！ そうだっけ？
Did you?
（信）マジか！
お前 すげえとこにいたんだな
For real?!
You were at a pretty awesome place.
ああ…
縛られて どうなるかと思ったけど
Yeah. I wasn't sure what was gonna happen when they tied us up.
戦が終わったら 解放された
運が良かったのかもしれねえ
But when the war ended, they let us go.
Maybe I got lucky.
そうか…
I see...
（貂）簡単な気持ちで 軍師に
なろうとしてたわけじゃねえけど
I didn't decide to become a strategist with some half-hearted feelings, but...
今回の戦で
軍師の怖さを思い知った
in this war, I learned how scary it is to be a strategist.
（信）諦めんのか？
Are you giving up?
はぁ？ …んなわけねえだろう！
Huh?! Of course not!
むしろ逆だ！
（信）逆？
It's totally the opposite!
The opposite?
俺は軍師になる！
I will become a strategist!
I was finally able to stand at the same place as you.
やっとお前と同じ場所に立てたんだ
簡単に諦めてたまるかよ！
Like hell I'd give it up that easily!
初めてだな
お前が そんな目ぇすんの
It's the first time you've made eyes like that.
そ… そっか？
（信）見つけたんだな お前
R-Really?
So you've found it, huh?
ああ　俺は やるぜ！
（信）よし！
Yeah, I'm gonna do it!
Okay!
3 Months Later
Flag: Fei
飛信(ひしん)隊 右だ！
全員で切り開くぞ！
Feixin Unit, right!
We're all going to cut through together!
信どの！ 敵別部隊が
右側面より現れましたぞ！
Lord Xin, a separate unit from the enemy has appeared on the right side!
（信）ンッ…
（尾平）やべえ！
Uh oh!
Xin! We'll draw their attention.
（羌瘣(きょうかい)）信！ こちらが引き付ける
その間に行け！
Use that time to go!
頼む！
（羌瘣）私に続け！
Thanks!
Follow me!
漂(ひょう) 見てるか？
俺は三百人将になったぜ
Piao, are you watching?
I've become a Three Hundred Man General.
けど まだだ
But I've still got a long way to go.
王騎将軍から もらった矛が
俺には まだまだ重すぎる
The lance given to me by General Wang Qi is still too heavy for me!
（政）“これを預かれ”？
You want me to hold onto this?
ああ　俺ん家(ち)に
置いとくわけにいかねえからよ
Yeah.
I can't leave it at my house.
（信）俺が こいつを自由に
使いこなせるまで 預かってくれ
So hold onto this for me until I can handle it freely.
信… お前にも話しておこう
王騎のことを
Xin, I have something to talk to you about as well.
About Wang Qi.
I see...
（信）そうか
王騎将軍は お前に そんなことを…
So General Wang Qi said that to you...
（政）ああ…
かなわぬ夢になってしまったが
Yes.
It turned out to be a dream that would not come true, but...
（信）いや
（政）うん？
No.
王騎将軍は お前に中華を託し
俺には あの矛を託した
General Wang Qi entrusted China to you,
and entrusted that lance to me.
Do you understand what that means?
その意味が分かるか？
ハッ… 王と剣…
A king and a sword?
ああ　俺たちは この国の未来を…
Yeah. We were entrusted with this state's...
いや
中華全土の未来を託された王と剣だ
no, all of China's future as king and sword.
政… ２人で中華を目指そうぜ！
Zheng, let's seek all of China together!
Okay!
I won't stop!
俺は立ち止まらないぜ
天下の大将軍になる日まで
突っ走って 突っ走って…
Until the day I become greatest general under the heavens,
I'll keep charging, charging,
charging forward!
突っ走りきってやる！
赤き　血潮
akaki chishio
Crimson blood flowing...
この鼓動は　野望なのか
kono kodou wa yabou na no ka
Is this racing pulse ambition?
幼き日　誓った
osanaki hi chigatta
Even now, I do not waver
夢は今も　揺るがない
yume wa ima mo yuru ga nai
from that dream I dedicated myself to in my youth.
命が燃える
inochi ga moeru
My life burns bright.
Ｎｅｖｅｒ　Ｅｎｄｉｎｇ　Ｓｏｕｌ　情熱よ
Never Ending Soul jounetsu yo
Never Ending Soul of passion,
導け　天地を拓け
michibike tenchi wo hirake
guide me and open the path to heaven.
Ｎｅｖｅｒ　Ｅｎｄｉｎｇ　Ｗｏｒｌｄ　打ち立てよう
Never Ending World uchitateyou
Let's create a Never Ending World!
永遠の絆が誇り
eien no kizuna ga hokori
Boasting an eternal bond,
おまえと夢見た世界を　この手に　掴もう
omae to yumemita sekai wo kono te ni tsukamou
you and I will grasp the world we dreamed of.
～♪
End
Season 2 starts in June 2013.